

ESUBALEW DESSALEGN

Springfield, VA, United States | scotchtour1@gmail.com



PROFILE

I'm a highly organized, creative and motivated Full-Stack Web Developer with two years of experience in website development. I have a proven ability to successfully work within the web development environment as an individual and as a team member.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Co-founder and Full-Stack Web Developer 03/2019 - present

DCNine Web Solutions, Arlington, VA, United States

DC Nine is an independent web development agency that I helped establish. It is an agency that believes great work comes from a clear understanding of the needs and goals of the client. That is our mantra and the cornerstone of who we are collectively.

Immersive Student in Full 10/2019 - 03/2020**Stack Web Development**

Evangadi Tech, Silver Spring, MD, United States

Built multiple enterprise level projects in class. Recreated the live website of www.apple.com starting from the design, all the way to creating React components and deploying the project. Please refer to my Github account (https://github.com/esku953) to see the code I wrote.

Lead Developer 02/2020 - 03/2020DCNine Web Solutions, Arlington, VA, United States

Created a dynamic

website(https://hilyafdrivingschool.com) using WordPress to boost the company's visitor by 40%.

01/2020 - 02/2020Lead Developer DCNine Web Solutions, Arlington, VA, United States

Developed a dynamic and interactive website (https://megenagnaethiopianmarket.com) using Bootstrap ensuring high traffic, page views, and user experience resulting a 15% increasing in sales revenue.



EDUCATION

Business/Commerce,

10/2006 - 06/2009

General

University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia



SKILLS

Front-end Technology

HTML5, CSS3/SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ¡Query, React.js,

Back-end Technology

Node.js/NPM, Express, MongoDb, ISON/XML, RESTAPI, PHP, Apache,

Database

SQL, MySQL, MongoDB

CMS tools

WordPress, Shopify

Other Skills

MVC, Bash Scripting, Github, Agile Development, Scrum, Adobe Photoshop (CC)

Languages

Amharic, English

Native, Professional



SOCIAL MEDIA



@esubalew



@esku





Soccer



Tennis



Billiards